Guide to the Caldwell B. Esselstyn Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1945-1975; Series I; 9' (21 boxes)
  - Correspondence & Subject Files, 1964-1975
    - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Welfare Administration, Conference on Group Practice and Title XIX, 1967 June 29 (Box 19, Folder 459)
    - United States, Executive Office of the President, 1964 January - 1965 (Box 19, Folder 460-462)
      See also: box 41, folder 292
    - United States, Executive Office of the President, Office of Economic Opportunity, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 463)
      See also: box 19, folder 463
    - United Steelworkers of America, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 464)
    - Upper Hudson Regional Comprehensive Health Planning Organization, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 465)
    - V (Box 19, Folder 466)
    - Van Dyke, Frank, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 467)
    - Van Goor, Robert E. (Box 19, Folder 467)
    - Verhelle, Joseph (Box 19, Folder 467)
    - Voorhis, H. Jerry, 1964-1971 (Box 20, Folder 468)
      See also: box 53, folders 37-194
    - Wa (Box 20, Folder 469)
    - We - Wh (Box 20, Folder 470)
    - Wi - Wy (Box 20, Folder 471)
    - Wade, Preston (Box 20, Folder 471)
      See also: box 16, folders 393-398
    - Wandel, William H., 1964-1967 (Box 20, Folder 472)
    - Wayne State University, 1967-1972 (Box 20, Folder 473)
    - Weinerman, E. Richard, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 474)
    - Westchester Community Health Planning Corporation, 1972-1975 February 18 (Box 20, Folder 475-476)
    - Whipple (Allen O.) Surgical Society, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 477)
    - White House Conference on Health, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 478)
    - Wilson, Glenn (Box 20, Folder 478)
    - Witten, Carroll L., 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 479)
    - Woman's Medical College of Pennsylvania, Senior Seminars, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 480)
    - Woodcock, Leonard (Box 20, Folder 480)
    - Wynn, Ed, 1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 481)
    - Y - Z (Box 20, Folder 482)
    - Yale University (Box 20, Folder 482)
      box 48, folder 382
    - Yale University, Kiphuth (Bob) Memorial Fund, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 483)
    - Yededia, Avram (Box 20, Folder 483)
      See: box 14, folder 350
    - Yerby, Alonzo S., 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 484)
    - Zwerdling, Miller, Klimst and Maurer (Box 20, Folder 484)
  - Personal Correspondence
    - General Correspondence
      - A - C (Box 20, Folder 485)
      - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, Alumni Association, 1955-1964 (Box 20, Folder 486)
      - D - E (Box 20, Folder 487)
      - Employment possibilities, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 488)
      - Esselstyn, Caldwell B., Jr. (Bus), 1947-1972 (Box 20, Folder 489)
      - Esselstyn, Erik C., 1955-1974 (Box 20, Folder 490)
      - Esselstyn, Everett J. (June), 1948-1961 (Box 20, Folder 491)
      - Esselstyn, Lillian, 1956-1960 (Box 20, Folder 492)
      - Esselstyn, Sarah B., 1946-1960 (Box 20, Folder 493)
      - F-H (Box 20, Folder 494)
      - Heyman (David M.) Award, Circa 1959 (Box 20, Folder 495)
      - Howell, R. Rodney, 1960-1974 (Box 20, Folder 496)
      - Howell, Sarah V. (Mrs. R. Rodney), 1957-1964 (Box 20, Folder 496)
      - I - K (Box 20, Folder 497)
      - L - N (Box 21, Folder 498)
      - New York State Employees' Retirement System, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 499)
      - O - P (Box 21, Folder 500)
      - Peckett, Mary (Mrs. Robert P.), 1957-1966 (Box 21, Folder 501)
      - Presbyterian Alumni Association, 1953-1967 (Box 21, Folder 502)
      - Q - R (Box 21, Folder 503)
      - S (Box 21, Folder 504)
      - Sturhahn, H.C. (Cobbles), 1948-1958 (Box 21, Folder 505)
      - T (Box 21, Folder 506)
      - W-Y (Box 21, Folder 507)
      - Yale Alumni Associates in Medicine, 1953-1968 (Box 21, Folder 508)
      - Yale Club, 1963-1972 (Box 21, Folder 508)
      - Yale Corporation, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 508)
      - Yale University Alumni Association, 1948-1974 (Box 21, Folder 509-510)
      - Yale University Athletic Association, 1956-1967 (Box 21, Folder 511)
      - Yale University Committee on Enrollment and Scholarships, 1958-1963 (Box 21, Folder 512)
      - Yale University, New York Regional Association of Elihu, 1956-1967 (Box 21, Folder 513)
    - Subject Correspondence
      - Expense accounts and honoraria, 1955-1959, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 514-517)
      - Hospital appointments and lectureships, 1951-1962 (Box 21, Folder 518)
- Principal Professional Activities, 1946-1974; Series II; 11' (27 boxes)
  PRINCIPAL PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES is organized in five sections: Rip Van Winkle Foundation, Community Health Association, New York Metropolitan Regional Medical Program, New York State Department of Health, Bureau of Emergency Medical Services, and United States Department of Health Education and Welfare, Health Maintenance Organization Service. The larger sections are organized in subsections.
  - Rip Van Winkle Foundation
    - General Papers
      - Certificate of incorporation and bylaws, agreement with Associates, amendments, 1946-1961 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Board of Directors: annual reports, 1947-1950, 1957, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Medical staff meetings: minutes, 1948-1959 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Board of Directors: minutes and related material, 1950-1956 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - "Manual for Professional Staff", 1961 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Executive Committee of the Professional Staff: minutes and correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Committee re: medical staff salaries: notes and reports, 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous policy statements, 1962, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Board of Directors: correspondence, project proposals and R.V.W.C. obituary, 1964-1968 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence and subject files
        - American Association of Medical Clinics (Box 22, Folder 9)
          See: box 1, folders 6-13
        - American Cancer Society, New York State Division (Box 22, Folder 9)
          See: box 2, folder 15
        - American Federation of Medical Clinics (Box 22, Folder 9)
          See: box 2, folder 20
        - American Medical Association (Box 22, Folder 9)
          See: box 2, folder 21
        - Asbornsen, Matthew A., 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - Askue, William, 1953-1955 (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - Barr, David (Box 22, Folder 10)
          See: box 2, folder 34
        - Blair, Edwin F. (Box 22, Folder 10)
          See: box 3, folder 39
          box 12, folder 283
        - Briwa, Helen (Box 22, Folder 10)
          See: box 12, folder 290
        - Brokaw, Katherine, 1947-1953, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 11)
        - Cancilla, Michael, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
        - Clark, Bliss (Box 22, Folder 12)
          See: box 3, folder 56
        - Columbia County Arts and Crafts Guild, 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - Columbia County Department of Health, 1952-1955, 1957, 1960-1963 (Box 22, Folder 14-20)
        - Columbia County Department of Public Welfare, 1951-1962, 1956, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 21-23)
        - Columbia County Medical Society, 1946-1956 (Box 22, Folder 24)
        - Columbia County Medical Society, 1957-1964 (Box 23, Folder 25)
        - Columbia County Medical Society (re: C.B.E. censures), 1948-1961 (Box 23, Folder 26)
          See also: box 14, folder 347
        - Columbia County Society for Mental Health, 1958-1961 (Box 23, Folder 27)
        - Columbia Memorial Hospital, 1944-1961, 1946-1964 (Box 23, Folder 28-32)
        - Corfman, Phillip, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 33)
        - Davis, Michael M. (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 4, folder 82
        - Egan, Eleanor (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 13, folder 311
        - Farrell, J. Cottrell (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 4, folder 91
        - Ficke, Gladys (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 4, folder 92
        - Fiske, Robert (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 4, folder 94
        - Flaherty, J. Preston (Box 23, Folder 33)
        - Gehrig, Eleanor (Box 23, Folder 33)
          See: box 4, folder 97
        - Gerbarg, David S., 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 34)
        - Group practice inquiries, 1959-1964 (Box 23, Folder 34)
        - Harper's, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 35)
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, 1951-1954, 1958-1964 (Box 23, Folder 36-40)
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 41)
          See also: box 78, folder 267
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, Associated Medical Groups, 1962-1964 (Box 24, Folder 42)
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, Education Division, 1958-1960 (Box 24, Folder 43)
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, Federation of Medical Groups, 1955-1961 (Box 24, Folder 44-46)
        - Hilleboe, Herman (Box 24, Folder 44-46)
        - Hilles, Charles D., Jr. (Box 24, Folder 44-46)
          See: box 5, folder 113
        - Johnson, Robert R., 1958-1961 (Box 24, Folder 47)
        - Larimore, Granville (Box 24, Folder 47)
          See: box 6, folder 136
        - McWilliams, Charles M., 1949 (Box 24, Folder 48)
        - Means, James (Box 24, Folder 48)
        - Mudge, Stern, Baldwin and Todd (Box 24, Folder 48)
          See: box 6, folder 155
        - Milliken, David K., 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 49)
        - New York State Department of Health (Box 24, Folder 49)
          See: box 7, folder 165
        - New York State Department of Social Welfare, 1950-1962 (Box 24, Folder 50)
        - New York State Education Department, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 51)
        - New York State Medical Society (Box 24, Folder 51)
        - Parkhurst, Leonard (Box 24, Folder 51)
          See: box 7, folder 176
        - Prentice, J. Rockefeller (Box 24, Folder 51)
          See: box 7, folder 181
        - Prentice, P.I. (Box 24, Folder 51)
          See: box 7, folder 182
        - Requests for information, 1959-1964 (Box 24, Folder 52)
        - Rose, Alfred (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 17, folder 422
        - Rose, Milton (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 8, folder 197
          box 17, folder 422
        - Rosenthal, Paul (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 8, folder 198
        - Ryan, Allan (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 8, folder 200
        - St. John, Fordyce B. (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 9, folder 203
        - Sheps, Cecil (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 9, folder 205
        - Silver, George (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 9, folder 206
        - Spock, Benjamin (Box 24, Folder 52)
          See: box 9, folder 208
        - Stearns, Kendall, 1947-1954, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 53)
        - Stout, Arthur Purdy (Box 24, Folder 53)
          See: box 9, folder 210
        - Studer, Augustus C. (Box 24, Folder 53)
          See: box 9, folder 211
        - Studer, Margot (Mrs. Agustus C.) (Box 24, Folder 53)
          See: box 9, folder 212
        - Travis, Willis, 1949-1953 (Box 24, Folder 54)
        - Trussell, Ray E (Box 24, Folder 54)
          See: box 9, folder 220
        - United Medical Services, Inc. (Blue Shield), 1955-1964 (Box 24, Folder 55)
        - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health (Box 24, Folder 55)
          See: box 9, folder 223
        - Visitors to the clinic, 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 56-57)
        - Visitors to the clinic, 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 58-59)
        - Waldo, John and Irma, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 60)
          - Wynn, Ed (Box 25, Folder 60)
            See: box 9, folder 234
            box 20, folder 481
        - Yale University, School of Architecture, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - Business Records
      - General
        - Correspondence and related material, 1947-1952 (Box 25, Folder 62)
        - Correspondence re: retirement plans, 1951-1964 (Box 25, Folder 63)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1953-1964 (Box 25, Folder 64-65)
        - Contract with the Training School for Girls, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 66)
      - Financial
        - General
          - Correspondence and reports re: tax exempt status, 1946-1948, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 67)
          - Financial and statistical summaries and related material for R.V.W. Medical Associates, 1947-1956 (Box 25, Folder 68)
          - Budget summaries and working papers, 1948-1955, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 69)
          - Accounting records and projections, 1952, 1956-1963 (Box 25, Folder 70)
          - Income tax returns, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 71)
          - Correspondence re: loans from National Insurance Co., 1955-1964 (Box 26, Folder 72)
          - Financial and statistical summaries and related material for R.V.W. Medical Associates, 1957-1963, undated (Box 26, Folder 73)
        - Fund raising
          - General correspondence
            - Testimonial letters, 1947-1954 (Box 26, Folder 74)
            - Campaign letters, 1948-1953 (Box 26, Folder 75)
            - Correspondence, 1948-1964 (Box 26, Folder 76)
            - Contribution lists, 1949-1957 (Box 26, Folder 77)
            - Contribution replies, 1949-1959 (Box 26, Folder 78)
            - John Price Jones Co.: "Survey, Analysis and Plan of Solicitation" for R.V.W.F., 1954 (Box 26, Folder 79)
            - John Price Jones Co.: correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 80)
            - John Price Jones Co.: lists of prospective donors and drafts of promotional materials, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 81)
            - Campaign letters and replies, 1954-1964 (Box 26, Folder 82)
          - Select correspondence
            - American Foundations Information Service, 1954-1957 (Box 26, Folder 83)
            - Astor Foundation, 1949-1964 (Box 26, Folder 84)
            - Austin, Edward, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 85)
            - Avalon Foundation, 1954-1963 (Box 26, Folder 86)
            - Bench, Edward C., 1950-1954 (Box 26, Folder 87)
            - Bontecou, Frederic H., 1948-1952 (Box 26, Folder 88)
            - Carnegie Corporation, 1954-1957 (Box 26, Folder 89)
            - Carter, Mrs. Arthur, Jr., 1951-1954 (Box 26, Folder 90)
            - Columbia Box Board Mills Co., 1958-1961 (Box 26, Folder 91)
            - Commonwealth Fund, 1948-1954 (Box 26, Folder 92)
            - Commonwealth Fund, 1955-1963 (Box 27, Folder 93)
            - Cushing and Toth, 1955-1964 (Box 27, Folder 94)
            - Davis, Mr, and Mrs. Howland S., 1953 (Box 27, Folder 95)
            - Dudley Foundation, 1948, 1953-1960 (Box 27, Folder 96)
            - Ford Foundation, 1957-1963 (Box 27, Folder 97)
            - Garnjost, Frederick and Jane, 1949-1951 (Box 27, Folder 98)
            - Grant Foundation, Inc., 1952-1958 (Box 27, Folder 99)
            - Hanes, John, 1949-1957 (Box 27, Folder 100)
            - Harkness Foundation, Inc., 1949-1959 (Box 27, Folder 101)
            - Hilles, Charles D., Jr., 1950 (Box 27, Folder 102)
            - Houghton, Mrs. William H., 1950-1953 (Box 27, Folder 103)
            - James Foundation, 1953-1964 (Box 27, Folder 104)
            - Kellogg Foundation, 1954-1957 (Box 27, Folder 105)
            - Kresge Foundation, 1948-1957 (Box 27, Folder 106)
            - Kress (Samuel H.) Foundation, 1954-1957 (Box 27, Folder 107)
            - Lansing Foundation (Augustus C. Studer Memorial Fund), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 108)
            - Macy (Josiah, Jr.) Foundation, 1950-1963 (Box 27, Folder 109)
            - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1950-1965 (Box 27, Folder 110-113)
            - New York Foundation, Inc., 1948, 1953-1956 (Box 28, Folder 114)
            - Old Dominion Foundation, Inc., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 115)
            - Olin Foundation, Inc., 1956-1962 (Box 28, Folder 116)
            - Parsons, Joseph H., 1949-1955 (Box 28, Folder 117)
            - Pfeiffer Research Foundation, 1954-1958 (Box 28, Folder 118)
            - Prentice, Alta Rockefeller, 1946-1965 (Box 28, Folder 119-121)
            - Pulitzer, Hubert, 1950-1955 (Box 28, Folder 122)
            - Raynie Foundation, 1955, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 123)
            - Rockefeller Foundation, 1949-1963 (Box 28, Folder 124)
            - Ryan, Allan and Fortune, 1948-1952 (Box 28, Folder 125)
            - Schiff Foundation, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 126)
            - Sears Roebuck Foundation, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 127)
            - Sloan (Alfred P.) Foundation, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 128)
            - Stackpole-Hall Foundation, 1950-1964 (Box 28, Folder 129)
            - Stearns, Mr. and Mrs. Malcolm, 1949-1955 (Box 28, Folder 130)
            - Steiner (S. S.) Shops, Inc., 1948-1954 (Box 28, Folder 131)
            - Studer (Augustus C.) Memorial Fund, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 132)
            - Whitney (William C.) Foundation, 1950-1959 (Box 28, Folder 133)
            - Wiman, Dwight Deere, 1948-1951 (Box 28, Folder 134)
            - Woolworth, Norman B., 1950-1960 (Box 28, Folder 135)
      - Personnel
        - Correspondence
          - M.D. applications, 1946-1952 (Box 29, Folder 136)
          - Clinic staff, 1946-1954 (Box 29, Folder 137)
          - Non-M.D. applications, 1946-1954 (Box 29, Folder 138)
          - M.D. applications, 1953-1955 (Box 29, Folder 139-141)
          - Clinic staff, 1955-1960 (Box 29, Folder 142)
          - M.D. applications, 1960-1961 March (Box 29, Folder 143)
          - Form replies to advertisements, 1960-1962 (Box 29, Folder 144)
          - General recruitment, 1960-1963 (Box 30, Folder 145)
          - M.D. applications, 1961 April-December (Box 30, Folder 146-147)
          - Clinic staff, 1961-1964 (Box 30, Folder 148)
          - M.D. applications, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 149-151)
          - General recruitment, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 152)
      - Supplies and facilities
        - Facilities
          - Canaan clinic: correspondence, bills and inventories, 1956-1964 (Box 31, Folder 153-154)
          - Chatham clinic: correspondence, bills and inventories, 1958-1961 (Box 31, Folder 155)
          - Clinic library: inventories, 1957-1959 (Box 31, Folder 156)
          - Dinehart Mansion acquisition: correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 157)
          - Germantown clinic: correspondence and bills, 1953-1961 (Box 31, Folder 158)
          - Hillsdale clinic: correspondence, bills and inventories, 1944, 1950-1959 (Box 31, Folder 159)
          - Hudson clinic: correspondence, bills and inventories, 1955-1960 (Box 31, Folder 160)
          - Philmont clinic: correspondence, bills and inventories, 1950-1964 (Box 31, Folder 161)
          - Valatie clinic: affidavit, correspondence and bills, 1958-1961 (Box 31, Folder 162)
        - Supplies
          - Building construction: correspondence and plans, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 163)
          - Confidential records systems: correspondence, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 164)
          - General: inventories, correspondence and bills, 1946-1959 (Box 31, Folder 165)
          - Prefabricated buildings: correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 31, Folder 166)
  - Programs and Projects
    - Annual review examinations
      - Correspondence
        - Prospective patients, 1948-1954 (Box 31, Folder 167-168)
        - Past patients (A - K), 1955 (Box 31, Folder 169)
        - Past patients (I - Z), 1955 (Box 31, Folder 170)
        - Scheduling, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 171)
        - Patients, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 172)
        - Prospective patients, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 173)
        - Patients, 1957-1958 (Box 32, Folder 174-175)
      - Cancer Diagnostic Clinic
        - Correspondence
          - Approval and operation, 1943-1954 (Box 32, Folder 176)
          - American Cancer Society, 1947-1954 (Box 32, Folder 177)
          - American College of Surgeons, 1950-1954 (Box 32, Folder 178)
          - Patients re: scheduling, 1951-1953 (Box 32, Folder 179)
          - American Cancer Society, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 180)
          - Patients re: scheduling (A - J), 1955 (Box 32, Folder 181)
          - Patients re: scheduling (L - Z), 1955 (Box 32, Folder 182)
          - Patients re: scheduling (A - J), 1956 (Box 32, Folder 183)
          - Patients re: scheduling (K - Z), 1956 (Box 32, Folder 184)
          - American Cancer Society, 1956-1958 (Box 33, Folder 185-186)
          - Patients re: scheduling, 1957-1958 (Box 33, Folder 187)
          - Outline re: uterine cancer screening program, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 188)
      - Educational Fellowship Fund: correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 33, Folder 189)
      - "Functional Design of a Rural Community Health Center", 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 190)
      - Fortnightly Meetings
        - Correspondence and related material, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 191)
        - Schedules, 1946-1961 (Box 33, Folder 192)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1948-1953 (Box 33, Folder 193-197)
        - News releases and related material, 1953-1960 (Box 33, Folder 198)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1954-1956 (Box 33, Folder 199-201)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1957-1961 (Box 34, Folder 202-204)
      - Home Care Program
        - Personnel records, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 205)
        - Advisory board correspondence and minutes, 1962-1964 (Box 34, Folder 206)
        - Correspondence re: personnel, 1962-1964 (Box 34, Folder 207)
        - Financial records, 1962-1964 (Box 34, Folder 208)
        - Meeting minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 209)
        - Reports and print material, 1963-1964, undated (Box 34, Folder 210)
        - Regulations, Circa 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 211)
      - Mental Hygiene Section
        - General correspondence and reports, 1951-1956 (Box 34, Folder 212-213)
        - Psychosocial development of aggressive behavior: correspondence and application, 1956-1957 October (Box 34, Folder 214)
        - Psycococial development of aggressive behavior: correspondence and application, 1957 November-1963 (Box 35, Folder 215)
        - General correspondence and reports, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 216)
        - General correspondence and reports re: New York State Department of Mental Health, 1959-1964 (Box 35, Folder 217)
        - General reports and grant applications, 1959-1964 (Box 35, Folder 218)
      - Public Health Educator
        - Correspondence and related material, 1953-1956 June (Box 35, Folder 219-224)
        - "Developing Comprehensive Rural Group Practice": reports and correspondence, 1956 July 2 (Box 36, Folder 225-226)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1956 July-1958 (Box 36, Folder 227-229)
    - Publications and Photographs
      - Publications
        - Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York leaflet, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 231)
        - "Health Preferred", 1954-1955 (Box 36, Folder 232)
        - News releases, 1954-1961, undated (Box 36, Folder 233)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume I, 1-7, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 234)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume II, 1-4, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 235)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume III, 1-3, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 236)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume IV, 1-3, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 237)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume V, 1-3, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 238)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume VI, 1-2, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 239)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume VII, 1-4, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 240)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume VIII, 1-4, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 241)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume IX, 1-4, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 242)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume X, 1-4, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 243)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume XI, 1-4, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 244)
        - Proceedings of the Rip Van Winkle Clinic, Volume XII, 1-4, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 245)